Daniel Kuhman, Ph.D.

I am a researcher, analyst, and data scientist with 9 years of experience in quantitative analysis across a variety of fields. I bring the passion and expertise needed to help businesses derive meaningful and actionable insights from their data. Let's build something cool together!

danielkuhman@gmail.com · Portfolio · LinkedIn · GitHub · Publications · YouTube

Experience

Strike (Zap Solutions Inc.) / Data Analyst

April 2022 - June 2023, Remote

I served as an embedded analyst with the Trust & Safety, Fraud Ops, and Compliance teams, where I used data to guide fraud mitigation features like smarter user limits and selective access to "instant credit." These and other features led to a 90% reduction of deposit fraud on the platform.

City Enterprises / Director of Data Science

April 2021 - April 2022, Murfreesboro TN

I developed and implemented data-driven approaches to inventory optimization for multiple car lots and developed ML models to guide vehicle acquisition. I also helped develop, track, and forecast KPIs related to vehicle sales and built out data reporting capabilities.

University of Alabama Birmingham / Research Fellow

August 2017 - April 2021, Birmingham AL

I worked in the UAB Biomechanics Lab and Human Neuromodulation Lab while completing my doctoral studies and dissertation. To date, this work has resulted in 11 peer-reviewed publications.

East Carolina University / Graduate Research & Teaching Assistant

August 2015 - May 2017, Greenville NC

I worked in the ECU Biomechanics Lab while completing my masters work. My thesis work was funded through a competitive grant from the Society of Biomechanics and was published in the Journal of Biomechanics.

University of Memphis / Undergraduate Research Fellow

June 2014 - May 2015, Memphis TN

I received funding through the Helen Hardin Summer Research Fellowship to complete research in the Musculoskeletal Dynamics Lab and the Cardiorespiratory & Metabolic Lab as an undergraduate student. This work resulted in three peer-reviewed publications.

Education

Google Career Certificates

- Data Analytics: Completed on Coursera, August 2023 (view certificate)
- Business Intelligence: Completed on Coursera, September 2023 (view certificate)
- Advanced Data Analytics: Expected Completion October 2023

University of Alabama Birmingham / Ph.D. Rehabilitation Science

August 2017 - August 2021, With dissertation, GPA: 4.0

East Carolina University / M.S. Biomechanics

August 2015 - May 2017, With thesis, GPA: 4.0

University of Memphis / B.S.Ed. Health & Human Performance

August 2011 - May 2015, GPA: 3.8, Suma Cum Laude, Honors

Relevant Skills

- Languages: SQL, R, Python
- Git, Google Cloud Platform, BigQuery, Airflow, dbt
- BI Tools: Looker, Cluvio, Tableau, Google Analytics
- Self-starter, independent, fast learner, motivated